A Guide to the Governor Gerald L. Baliles Executive Papers, 1986-1990
Library of Virginia
- Series II. 1987 (accession 33702)
  - Sub-Series D: Governor's Office
    - Other States - General (part three) (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Other States - Offices (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Proclamations - See Messages from the Governor
    - Requests - Auction (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Requests - General/Samples (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Retirement Letters (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Secretaries of State Conference, Norfolk, 18 December 1987 (See Also Box 103, Folder 10) (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1987 December 31-December 15 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1987 December 14-November 25 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1987 November 20-November 12 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1987 November 10-October 29 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1987 October 28-September 29 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1987 September 28-August 25 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1987 August 21-July 1 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1987 June 30-May 27 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1987 May 19-April 23 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1987 April 22-March 23 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1987 March 18-February 3 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1987 February 2-January 3 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - State of the Commonwealth, 1987 January 14, and Correspondence (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Sympathy Letters (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Telegrams - General (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Thank You Letters to and from the Governor, 1987 December 26-July 9 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Thank You Letters to and from the Governor, 1987 June 19-January 2 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Transportation Letters (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Cultural Laureates (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Day in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Geographic Alliance (National Geographic Society) (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Virginia-Israel Commission (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Military Advisory Commission (part one) (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Military Advisory Commission (part two) (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Scholars (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Silver Star Foundation (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Washington-Dulles Task Force (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Shenandoah Valley Work Week (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Tidewater Work Week (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Form Letters 87-2 thru 10 (samples of) (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Form Letters 87-11 thru 20 (samples of) (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Form Letters 87-21 thru 22 (samples of) (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Form Letters 87-23 thru 24 (samples of) (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Form Letters 87-25 (samples of) (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Form Letters 87-26 thru 30 (samples of) (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Form Letters 87-31 thru 34 (samples of) (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Form Letters 87-35 thru 36 (samples of) (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Form Letters 87-37 (samples of) (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Form Letters 87-38 thru 39 (samples of) (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Form Letters 87-40 (samples of) (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Form Letters 87-41 thru 49 (samples of) (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Sub-Series E: Cabinet
    - Secretary to the Cabinet, H. Benson Dendy, III (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - E.1 - Secretary of Administration
    - Correspondence and Memorandums to Governor's Office, 1987 December 28-July 6 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence and Memorandums to Governor's Office, 1987 June 24-January 16 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Nurses Salaries (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - E.1 - Secretary of Administration - State Agencies
    - Compensation Board (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Department of General Services (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Department of Information Technology (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Department of Personnel and Training (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Department of Personnel and Training - Virginia Executive Institute (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Office of Employee Relations Counselors (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - State Board of Elections (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Supplemental Retirement System (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - E.2 - Secretary of Economic Development
    - Correspondence and Memorandums send and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 December 29-August 25 (See Also Oversize Box 1) (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence and Memorandums send and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 August 13-June 25 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence and Memorandums send and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 June 5-April 17 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence and Memorandums send and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 April 13-January 8 (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - Deputy Secretary of Economic Development, Corresondence and Memorandums send and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - E.2 - Secretary of Economic Development - State Agencies
    - Commission for the Arts (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services (part one) (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services (part two) (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services (part three) (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Department of Commerce (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Department of Economic Development, 1987 December 23-August 18 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Department of Economic Development, 1987 August 11-May 22 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Department of Economic Development, 1987 May 18-March 25 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Department of Economic Development, 1987 March 23-January 6 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Department of Economic Development - Southeast United States/Japan Association (SEUS/Japan), Annual Meeting, Tokyo, Japan, 1987 October (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Department of Economic Development - Small Business Financing Authority (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Department of Economic Development - Division of Tourism (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Department of Economic Development - Virginia Film Office (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Department of Forestry (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Department of Housing and Community Development (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Department of Labor and Industry (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Department of Mines, Minerals and Energy (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Department of Minority Business Enterprise (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Southern Growth Policies Board (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Southwest Virginia Economic Development Commission (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Virginia Employment Commission (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Housing Development Authority (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - E.2 - Secretary of Economic Development - Economic Development Topics
    - Appalachian Regional Commission (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - "Explore" Project - Roanoke River (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - E.3 - Secretary of Education
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 December 29-October 5 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 September 30-May 4 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 April 27-January 5 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Deputy Secretary of Education, Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - E.3 - Secretary of Education - Colleges and Universities
    - General (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - State Council of Higher Education in Virginia (SCHEV) (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - George Mason University (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - James Madison University (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Longwood College (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Medical College of Virginia - See Virginia Commonwealth University
    - Norfolk State University (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Old Dominion University (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - University of Virginia (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Commonwealth University/Medical College of Virginia (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Community College System (VCCS) (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Military Institute (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University (part one) (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University (part two) (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University - Governor's Commencement Address (1987 June 13) (part one) (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University - Governor's Commencement Address (1987 June 13) (part two) (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University - Governor's Commencement Address (1987 June 13) (part three) (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Virginia State University (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - College of William and Mary (part one) (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - College of William and Mary (part two) (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - E.3 - Secretary of Education - Education Topics
    - Education Commission of the States (ECS) (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Elementary School Guidance Counselors (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Governor's Language Academies (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Museum of American Frontier Culture (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - National Student/Parent Mock Election (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Project Discovery (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - School Health Clinics/Sex Education (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Southeastern Universities Research Association, Inc. (SURA)/Continuous Electronic Beam Accelerator Facility (CEBAF) (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Southern Regional Education Board (SREB) (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - State Board of Education (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - E.3 - Secretary of Education - State Agencies
    - Department of Education (part one) (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Department of Education (part two) (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - The Science Museum of Virginia (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - State Education Assistance Authority (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Educational Loan Authority (VELA) (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Virginia State Library and Archives (part one) (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Virginia State Library and Archives (part two) (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - E.4 - Secretary of Finance
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 December 28-August 24 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 August 21-January 16 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Deputy Secretary of Finance, Correspondence and Memorandums sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - E.4 - Secretary of Finance - State Agencies
    - Department of Accounts - Comptroller (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Department of Planning and Budget (part one) (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Department of Planning and Budget (part two) (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Department of Planning and Budget - Surplus (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Department of Planning and Budget - Governor's Commission on Federal Spending of State Domestic Programs (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Department of the State Internal Auditor (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Department of Taxation (part one) (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Department of Taxation (part two) (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Department of Taxation (part three) (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Department of Taxation (part four) (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Department of the Treasury (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Department of the Treasury - Division of Unclaimed Property (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - E.5 - Secretary of Human Resources
    - [See Series VI. Miscellaneous (accession 33707) for additional Secretary of Human Resources records.]
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 December 29-August 28 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 August 27-June 29 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 June 26-March 26 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 March 23-January 5 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - E.5 - Secretary of Human Resources - State Agencies
    - Department of Health Regulatory Boards (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Department of Medical Assistance Services (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Department of Mental Health, Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse Services (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Department of Rehahilitation Services (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Department for the Rights of the Disabled (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Department of Social Services (part one) (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Department of Social Services (part two) (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Department of Social Services (part three) (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Department of Social Services (part four) (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Department of Volunteerism (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Governor's Employment and Training Department (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Governor's Employment and Training Department - Job Training Partnership Act (JTPA) (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Health Services Cost Review Council (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - E.5 - Secretary of Human Resources - Human Resources Topics
    - Medicaid Benefits (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Mentally Disabled (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Reston Hospital (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - E.6 - Secretary of Natural Resources
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 December 31-November 23 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 November 19-August 11 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 July 31-February 23 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 February 20-January 9 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Deputy Secretary of Natural Resources, Correspondence and Memorandums sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - E.6 - Secretary of Natural Resources - State Agencies
    - Commission of Game and Inland Fisheries (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Council of the Environment (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Department of Conservation and Historic Resources (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Department of Emergency Services - Drought, 1987 December 5-September 25 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Department of Emergency Services - Drought, 1987 September 21-September 17 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Department of Emergency Services - Drought, 1987 September 1-April 27 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Department of Waste Management (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Marine Resources Commission (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - State Air Pollution Control Board (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - State Water Control Board (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Resources Authority (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - E.6 - Secretary of Natural Resources - Natural Resources Topics
    - False Cape State Park (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Lorton Incinerator (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Manassas Battlefield Park (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Phosphate Ban (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Public Beaches (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Shenandoah Quarry (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Wetlands (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - E.7 - Secretary of Transportation and Public Safety
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 December 31-October 2 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 September 30-June 8 (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 May 28-January 5 (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 December 29-September 1 (Box 81, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 August 31-May 4 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 April 22-January 5 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Deputy Secretary of Transportation, Correspondence and Memorandums sent and/or copied to Governor's Office, 1987 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - E.7 - Secretary of Transportation and Public Safety - State Agencies
    - Alcoholic Beverage Control Board (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Department of Aviation (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Department of Corrections (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Department of Corrections - Charles City prison Site (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Department of Corrections - Tazewell Prison Site (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Department of Corrections - Virginia State Penitentiary (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Department of Criminal Justice Services (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Department of Emergency Services (part one) (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Department of Emergency Services (part two) (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Department of Military Affairs (part one) (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Department of Military Affairs (part two) (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Department of Motor Vehicles (part one) (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Department of Motor Vehicles (part two) (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Department of State Police (part one) (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Department of State Police (part two) (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Department of Transportation (part one) (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Department of Transportation (part two) (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Department of Transportation (part three) (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Department of Transportation (part four) (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Department of Transportation (part five) (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Department of Transportation (part six) (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Department of Transportation (part seven) (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Department of Transportation (part eight) (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Department of Transportation (part nine) (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Department of Transportation - Route 28 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Department of Transportation - Route 29 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Department of Transportation - Route 58 (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Department of Transportation - Route 288 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Port Authority (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - E.7 - Secretary of Transportation and Public Safety - Transportation Topics
    - Eastern Shore Railroad Abandonment (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Impact Fees/Recordation Taxes (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Logo Program (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Transportation Week (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Sub-Series F: General Assembly
    - 1987 Legislation (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence, House of Delegates and State Senate (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - House of Delegates Correspondence, A-B (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - House of Delegates Correspondence, C (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - House of Delegates Correspondence, D-K (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - House of Delegates Correspondence, L-Q (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - House of Delegates Correspondence, R-W (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - Senate Correspondence, A-C (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Senate Correspondence, D-M (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Senate Correspondence, N-W (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Sub-Series G: Secretary of the Commonwealth
    - Gubernatorial Appointments (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Sub-Series H: Legislative
    - Auditor of Public Accounts (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Department of Workman's Compensation - Industrial Commission of Virginia (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Division of Legislative Services (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Committee (JLARC) (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Virginia State Crime Commission (Box 87, Folder 9)
  - Sub-Series I: Attorney General
    - Attorney General's Office - Correspondence (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - Department of Law - Division of War Veterans' Claims (Box 87, Folder 11)
  - Sub-Series J: Judicial
    - General (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Virginia State Bar (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Sub-Series K: State Corporation Commission
    - General (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Bureau of Financial Institutions (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Bureau of Insurance (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Sub-Series L: Lt. Governor
    - L. Douglas Wilder (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Sub-Series M: Virginia Liaison Office
    - Correspondence and Memorandums, 1987 (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - Sub-Series N: United States Government
    - Senate - General (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Senate - John W. Warner (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - Senate - Paul S. Trible (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - House of Representatives - General (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Congressional Delegation Letters - General (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Congressional Delegation Letters, Bateman through Wolf (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Corporate Takeover Legislation (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Department of Agriculture (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Department of the Air Force (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Department of the Army (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Department of the Army - Corps of Engineers (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Department of Commerce (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - Department of Defense (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - Department of Education (Box 89, Folder 11)
    - Department of Energy (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Department of Health and Human Services (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Department of Housing and Urban Development (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Department of Immigration and Naturalization Service (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Department of the Interior (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Department of Justice (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Department of Labor (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Department of the Navy (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - Department of the Navy, EMPRESS II (Electromagnetic Pulse Radiation Environment Simulator for Ships), 1987 (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - Department of State (Box 90, Folder 10)
    - Department of Transportation (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Excise Taxes (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - General (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - General Services Administration (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - National Transportation Safety Board (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Office of the Attorney General (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - Office of Technology Assessment (Box 91, Folder 9)
    - Postal Service (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Small Business Administration (Box 91, Folder 11)
    - Social Security Administration (Box 91, Folder 12)
    - Taxation of Interstate Mail Orders (Box 91, Folder 13)
    - U.S. Savings Bonds (Box 91, Folder 14)
    - White House (Box 91, Folder 15)
- Series III. 1988 (accession 33702)